Inventory of the American National Red Cross records
Hoover Institution Archives
American National Red Cross records
1906-1995
1917-1922
XX482
Hoover Institution Archives
219 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 5 oversize boxes, 1 framed photograph, and 2 videotape cassettes (95.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, financial records, lists, and photographs relating to relief work in Europe and the Middle East, Russia, and China during and immediately after World War I. Also available on microfilm (339 reels).
American National Red Cross.
Access
Microfilm use only.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Searchworks at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Searchworks is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Material
The Hazel Braugh Record Center and Archives of the American Red Cross http://www.redcross.org/museum/exhibits/braugh.asp provides additional information on the records center holdings as well as other repositories that hold American Red Cross records, such as the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) and the Library of Congress.
American Relief Administration Russian Operational records, 1919-1925, Hoover Institution Archives
American Relief Administration European Operations Records, 1919-1923, Hoover Institution Archives
Mary Catherine Roberts papers, 1918-1978, Hoover Institution Archives
Burle Bramhall collection, 1973-1976, Hoover Institution Archives
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (339 reels).
Historical Note
The American Red Cross is a humanitarian organization led by volunteers and guided by its Congressional Charter and the Fundamental Principals of the International Red Cross Movement. The Federal Charter states it is a nonprofit, tax-exempt, charitable organization. The organization's seven fundamental principles are: humanity, impartiality, neutrality, independence, voluntary service, unity, and universality. This mission guides the organization to provide relief to victims of disasters and to help people prevent, prepare for, and respond to emergencies.
At the beginning of the World War I, the American Red Cross was a small organization still in the process of developing its identity and programs. When the United States declared war against Germany on April 6, 1917, the organization began a period of extraordinary growth. By the time the war ended in November 1918, the Red Cross had become a major national humanitarian organization with strong leadership, a huge membership base, universal recognition, and a broad and distinguished record of service. The Red Cross continues to respond to emergencies today.
Scope and Content of Collection
The records of the American National Red Cross (ARC) in this collection deal mainly with relief around the world during and after World War I.
The records of the ARC are arranged by geographical location where each particular commission operated: commissions for the Balkan States (including countries such as Albania, Austria-Hungary, Bosnia-Herzegovina, Bulgaria, Greece, Montenegro, Romania, Serbia), Belgium, China, Czechoslovakia, France, Germany, Great Britain, Italy, Palestine and Egypt, Switzerland, and Russia (Petrograd Children's Colony, Siberia, Southern Russia, Western Russia, and Baltic States). The documents reflect the massive efforts put forth by the ARC to deliver aid to regions devastated by the war.
If the commission for a certain region or country operated in another territory (for example the Commission for Czechoslovakia opened hospitals on the territory of Russia), the documents may be found among the records of that geographic location. Along with official reports and financial records, correspondence of gratitude for the ARC gives a human side to the organization.
The collection also contains records of related organizations including the American Relief Administration, International and Junior Red Cross, YMCA, and American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee. The material presents a comprehensive history of relief work around the world, as well as economic and health conditions, political and social developments.
The Miscellany series includes documents of most geographic areas of the American National Red Cross that were not included in the original arrangement, and contains supplemental records of each commission.
Printed matter contains bulletins, magazines, reports, pamphlets, instructions, and manuals published by the ARC.
Arrangement
Records are arranged as originally received from the organization; generally by Commission or Office in geographical locations as well as the Headquarters Offices. General materials, oversize items, and printed materials may be found after the geographic locations
International relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--War work.
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Other Finding Aids note
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- Commissions for the Balkan States, 1917-1923
  Scope and Contents note
  See also South Eastern Base, Constantinople Unit
  - Cables, letters, clippings, stories (36 volumes), 1917-1919
    - General Staff, letters, vol.1-3 (Reel 1)
      Box 1
    - General Staff, letters, vol.1-3 (Reel 2)
    - General Staff, letters, vol.4-5 (Reel 3)
      Box 2
    - General Staff, letters, vol.4-5 (Reel 4)
    - Albania, Bosnia, Montenegro, cables (Reel 4)
      Box 3
    - Albania, Bosnia, Montenegro, cables (Reel 5)
    - Bosnia, Montenegro, letters (Reels 4)
    - Bosnia, Montenegro, letters (Reel 5)
    - Albania, Bosnia, cables (Reels 4)
    - Albania, Bosnia, cables (Reel 5)
    - Albania, Bosnia, Greece, stories (Reel 4)
    - Albania, Bosnia, Greece, stories (Reel 5)
    - Montenegro, Romania, stories (Reels 6)
      Box 4
    - Montenegro, Romania, stories (Reel 7)
    - Athens, cables (Reel 6)
    - Athens, cables (Reel 7)
    - Albania, letters (Reel 6)
    - Albania, letters (Reel 7)
    - Greece, Romania, cables (Reels 7)
      Box 5
    - Greece, Romania, cables (Reel 8)
    - Romania, letters, vol.1-2 (Reel 7)
    - Romania, letters, vol.1-2 (Reel 8)
    - Salonica (Thessalonike), cables (Reel 9)
      Box 6
    - London, Montenegro, Romania, cables
    - Orders files, 1917-1919 (Reel 10)
      Box 7
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Paris, cables (Reels 11)
      Box 8
    - Paris, cables (Reel 12)
    - Paris, cables (Reels 12)
      Box 9
    - Paris, cables (Reel 13)
    - Paris, cables (Reel 14)
    - Rome, cables (Reel 12)
    - Rome, cables (Reel 13)
    - Rome, cables (Reel 14)
    - Serbia, letters, vol.1 (Reel 12)
    - Serbia, letters, vol.1 (Reel 13)
    - Serbia, letters, vol.1 (Reel 14)
    - Serbia, letters, vol.2, cables, stories (Reel 14)
      Box 10
    - Serbia, letters, vol.2, cables, stories (Reel 15)
    - Serbia, letters, vol.2, cables, stories (Reel 16)
    - Toulon, cables (Reels 16)
      Box 11
    - Toulon, cables (Reel 17)
    - Trieste, Rome, Serbia, letters (Reel 16)
    - Trieste, Rome, Serbia, letters (Reel 17)
    - Washington, letters (Reel 16)
    - Washington, letters (Reel 17)
    - Washington, letters (Reels 17)
      Box 12
    - Washington, letters (Reel 18)
    - Greece, letters
    - Greece, letters (Reel 18)
    - Miscellany, cables (Reels 18)
      Box 13
    - Miscellany, cables (Reel 19)
  - Civilian relief, reports on relief work in feeding and clothing, 1919 (Reel 20)
    Box/Folder 14: 1
  - Finances, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 2
  - Clothing, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 3
  - Medical work, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 4
  - Home Communication Division, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 5
  - Liquidation, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 6
  - Children's Welfare Bureau, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 7
  - Auto-Chir Unit, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 8
  - Artificial Limbs Department, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 9
  - Colonel Henry W. Anderson, Commissioner to Europe, correspondence, 1918-1920
    Box/Folder 14: 10-11
  - Child health, 1921
    Box/Folder 14: 12
  - Publicity, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 13
  - Military relief, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 14
  - Warehouses, report by Captain W.H. Day, August 15, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 15
  - Scholarships, 1921
    Box/Folder 14: 16
  - Programs, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 17-18
  - Supplies, 1918-1919
    Box/Folder 14: 19-20
  - Personnel, February 1919-April 1920
    Box/Folder 14: 21
  - Reports, general, 1918-1920 (Reel 21)
    Box/Folder 14: 22-23
  - Transportation, 1919
    Box/Folder 14: 24
  - Helen Scott Hay, Chief Nurse, Balkan Commission, report on Nursing service, 1918-1919
    Box/Folder 14: 25
  - Commission for Montenegro, 1919-1920
    - American Red Cross official photographs, undated
      - General (Reel 21)
        Box/Folder 15: 1
      - Children
        Box/Folder 15: 2
      - Civilians
        Box/Folder 15: 3
      - Farm scenes
        Box/Folder 15: 4
      - Flood
        Box/Folder 15: 5
      - Hospitals
        Box/Folder 15: 6
      - Montenegro honors Americans
        Box/Folder 15: 7
      - Personnel
        Box/Folder 15: 8
      - Social life
        Box/Folder 15: 9
      - Supplies
        Box/Folder 15: 10
      - Troops
        Box/Folder 15: 11
    - Annual report, 1919-1920 (Reel 21)
      Box/Folder 15: 12
    - Annual medical report, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 15: 13
    - Supplemental reports to annual report, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 15: 14
    - Miscellany reports, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 15: 15
  - Commission for Albania, 1919-1922
    - Medical supplies, inventory, 1920 (Reel 21)
      Box/Folder 15: 16-17
    - Home Service Bureau, reports, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 15: 18
    - Child welfare, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 15: 19
    - Junior Red Cross Program, 1919-1920 (Reel 22)
      Box/Folder 15: 20
    - Junior Red Cross Report, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 21
    - Medical work, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 22
    - Personnel, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 23
    - Military relief, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 15: 24
    - Program, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 25
    - Publicity, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 26
    - Schools, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 27
    - Transportation, 1919
      Box/Folder 15: 28
    - America's Contribution toward a Better World, Letter from Europe, by Ross Wilder Lane, Department of Public Information, undated
      Box/Folder 15: 29
    - Selim Bey Wassa, correspondence and reports on illness and death, 1920
      Box/Folder 15: 30
    - Reports, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 15: 31
    - Reports, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 16: 1-7
    - Reports, 1919-1922 (Reel 23)
      Box/Folder 16: 8-18
    - Reports, 1919-1922 (Reel 24)
      Box/Folder 17: 1-2
  - Commission for Austria-Hungary, 1919-1922
    - Civilian relief, 1919
      Box/Folder 17: 3
    - Supplies, 1919
      Box/Folder 17: 4
    - Transportation, 1919
      Box/Folder 17: 5
    - Appeals, 1919
      Box/Folder 17: 6
    - Reports, 1919-1921
      Box/Folder 17: 7-14
    - Reports, 1919-1921 (Reel 25)
      Box/Folder 17: 15-16
    - Supplies, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 17: 17
    - Appreciation letters, 1921
      Box/Folder 17: 18
    - Symbolized station list, 1921
      Box/Folder 17: 19
    - Child health, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 17: 20
    - Child health, 1919-1922
      Box/Folder 18: 1-2
    - "Preliminary Survey of Health Conditions in Austria, April-May 1921," by Gordon M. Fair, Assistant Chief, Division of Sanitation, League of Red Cross Societies
      Box/Folder 18: 3-4
    - "Preliminary Survey of Health Conditions in Austria, April-May 1921," by Gordon M. Fair, Assistant Chief, Division of Sanitation, League of Red Cross Societies (Reel 26)
      Box/Folder 18: 5
  - Commission for Bosnia-Herzegovina, 1919
    - Correspondence, 1919
      Box/Folder 18: 6-8
  - Commission for Bulgaria, 1920-1922
    - Miscellany reports, 1920
      Box/Folder 18: 9
    - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 18: 10-11
    - Miscellany correspondence, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 18: 12
  - Commission for Greece, 1918-1923
    - Athens, 1918-1923
      - Home Service reports, 1919-1921
        Box/Folder 18: 13
      - Correspondence, 1918-1920
        Box/Folder 18: 14-15
      - Appropriations, 1920-1922
        Box/Folder 18: 16
      - American Women's Hospital at Vodena, 1829
        Box/Folder 18: 17
      - Appeals, 1920-1921
        Box/Folder 18: 18-19
      - Child Health, 1920-1922
        Box/Folder 18: 20-21
      - Correspondence, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 18: 22
      - Ernest P. Bicknell, Acting Director, Foreign Operations, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 18: 23
      - Ernest P. Bicknell, Acting Director, Foreign Operations, 1922-1923 (Reel 27)
        Box/Folder 19: 1-2
      - Ministry of Public Economy, 1922
        Box/Folder 19: 3
      - Ministry of Communication, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 19: 4
      - Ministry of Marine, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 19: 5
      - Ministry of War, 1923
        Box/Folder 19: 6
      - Ministry of Education and Public Instructions, 1923
        Box/Folder 19: 7
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1923
        Box/Folder 19: 8
      - Ministry of Food, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 19: 9
      - Ministry of Hygiene and Public Assistance, 1923
        Box/Folder 19: 10
      - Health Propaganda, 1923.
        Box/Folder 19: 11. Includes poster in Greek
      - "The Greeks in Asia Minor," article, undated
        Box/Folder 19: 12
      - Greek Government--Activities on behalf of refugees, 1923
        Box/Folder 19: 13
      - Foreign relief organizations--Activities, 1922
        Box/Folder 19: 14
      - Greek relief organizations (unofficial), activities, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 19: 15
      - Economic rehabilitation of refugees, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 19: 16
      - Medical work, 1920-1921
        Box/Folder 19: 17
      - Military relief, 1920-1921
        Box/Folder 19: 18
      - Miscellany, 1920-1921
        Box/Folder 19: 19
      - Reports, 1920-1921 (Reel 28)
        Box/Folder 19: 20-23
      - Reports, 1921
        Box/Folder 20: 1-2
      - Personnel, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 20: 3
      - Near East relief, 1922-1923
        Box/Folder 20: 4-6
      - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920-1921
        Box/Folder 20: 7
      - Reports, 1922
        Box/Folder 20: 8
      - Revolutionary Committee, 1923
        Box/Folder 20: 9
    - Salonica (Thessalonike), 1920-1922
      - Program, 1921
        Box/Folder 20: 10
      - Reports, 1920
        Box/Folder 20: 11-12
      - News Service, 1917-1921
        Box/Folder 20: 13
      - Reports, 1921-1922
        Box/Folder 20: 14
      - Reports, 1921-1922 (Reel 29)
        Box/Folder 20: 15-19
      - Correspondence, 1919-1921
        Box/Folder 20: 20
      - Medical work, 1921
        Box/Folder 20: 21
      - Child health, 1921
        Box/Folder 20: 22
      - Medical work, 1920
        Box/Folder 21: 1
      - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920-1922
        Box/Folder 21: 2
      - Letters of appreciation, 1920-1921
        Box/Folder 21: 3
  - Commission for Hungary, 1920-1922
    - Civilian relief, 1920-1922 (Reel 30)
      Box/Folder 21: 4
    - Appeals, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 5-7
    - Correspondence, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 8-10
    - Child health, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 11
    - Hungarian Red Cross, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 12
    - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 13
    - Medical work, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 14
    - Program, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 15-17
    - Liquidation, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 18
    - Publicity, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 21: 19
    - Reports, 1920-1922 (Reel 31)
      Box/Folder 21: 20-24
    - Appreciation letters, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 22: 1
    - Miscellany, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 22: 2
  - Commission for Montenegro, 1917-1922
    - Cash requests, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 22: 3
    - Child health, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 22: 4-5
    - Medical work, 1920
      Box/Folder 22: 6-8
    - Medical work, 1920 (Reel 32)
      Box/Folder 22: 9-12
    - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920
      Box/Folder 22: 13
    - Correspondence, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 22: 14
    - Relief, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 22: 15-16
    - Publicity, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 22: 17
    - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1921-1922
      Box/Folder 22: 18
    - Reports on Montenegro trip, 1920
      Box/Folder 22: 19
    - Russian refugee relief, 1920 (Reel 33)
      Box/Folder 23: 1
    - A Letter from Europe, by Department of Public Information, 1920
      Box/Folder 23: 2
    - Department of Personnel, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 23: 3
    - Reports, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 23: 4-11
    - Reports, 1920-1922 (Reel 34)
      Box/Folder 23: 12-13
    - Robbery reports and testimony, 1920-1921 (Reel 34)
      Box/Folder 23: 14
  - Commission for Romania, 1917-1921
    - Relief work, reports, 1917-1920
      Box/Folder 23: 15-16
    - Appeals, 1919
      Box/Folder 24: 1
    - Military relief, 1919
      Box/Folder 24: 2
    - Child welfare, 1919
      Box/Folder 24: 3
    - Children's hospital in Budapest, 1919
      Box/Folder 24: 4
    - "Refugee situation in Ackermann," report, 1920
      Box/Folder 24: 5
    - Civilian Relief Department, report on activities in the Sector of the CORJ, Western Romania, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 24: 6
    - Jewish relief, 1919
      Box/Folder 24: 7
    - Medical work, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 24: 8-10
    - Finances, Controller's report, 1919 (Reel 35)
      Box/Folder 24: 11
    - Appreciation letters, 1917-1918
      Box/Folder 24: 12
    - Minutes of the meetings of the ARC Mission for Romania en route from Chicago, Ill, to Jassy, Romania, via Vancouver, Tokyo, Vladivostok, Harbin, Moscow, Petrograd, and Kiev, official record, 1917
      Box/Folder 24: 13-16
    - ARC activities in Romania, map, 1919
      Box/Folder 24: 17
    - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 24: 18
    - "Sanitary Survey of Romania," report by George C. Whipple, Chief, Department of Sanitation of The League of Red Cross Societies, 1920
      Box/Folder 24: 19
    - Program, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 24: 20
    - Bureau of Transportation, 1917-1919
      Box/Folder 24: 21
    - Russian refugee relief at Tulcea, Romania, report, by Major Milton D. Brown, ARC, 1920
      Box/Folder 24: 22
    - Commissioner for Romania Gideon H. Wells, reports, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 25: 1-4
    - Supplies, 1919
      Box/Folder 25: 5
    - Supplies, 1919 (Reel 36)
      Box/Folder 25: 6-7
    - Reports, 1919
      Box/Folder 25: 8-10
    - Transportation, 1919
      Box/Folder 25: 11-12
    - Reports, 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 13-14
    - Reports, 1920 (Reel 37)
      Box/Folder 25: 15-16
    - Director of Civilian Relief Department, Milton D. Brown, report, 1920
      Box/Folder 25: 17
    - Director of Nursing Department Alice Fitzgerald, report on visit to Romania and Serbia, 1921 February 17-26
      Box/Folder 25: 18
  - Commission for Serbia, 1918-1922
    - American Women's Hospital Association, 1921
      Box/Folder 26: 1
    - Appeals, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 2-5
    - Appreciation letters, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 6
    - Child health, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 7
    - Civilian relief, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 8
    - Preliminary survey of health conditions in Yugoslavia made between December 9, 1920, and January 6, 1921, by General Medical Secretary George C. Shattuck, parts I and II, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 9-12
    - Medical work, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 26: 13-14
    - Medical work, 1920-1921 (Reel 38)
      Box/Folder 26: 15-22
    - Map of ARC activities in Serbia, 1919
      Box/Folder 26: 23
    - Bureau of Transportation, contracts, arrangements between Serbian Government and ARC in the care of Serbian and Montenegrin prisoners of war, 1918
      Box/Folder 27: 1
    - Prisoners and refugees of war, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 27: 2-3
    - Personnel, 1919-1921
      Box/Folder 27: 4
    - Correspondence, 1920 (Reel 39)
      Box/Folder 27: 5
    - Reports, 1920-1922
      Box/Folder 27: 6-14
    - Reports on orphans, 1919-1920
      Box/Folder 27: 15
    - Child Welfare Association of America, 1920-1922
      - Reports, 1920-1922
        Box/Folder 27: 16-17
      - Reports, 1920-1922 (Reel 40)
        Box/Folder 27: 18-20
      - Reports, 1920-1922
        Box/Folder 28: 1-3
      - Program, 1921-1922
        Box/Folder 28: 4-6
      - Supplies, 1922
        Box/Folder 28: 7
      - Publicity, 1922
        Box/Folder 28: 8
      - Finances, 1921-1922
        Box/Folder 28: 9-10
      - Personnel, 1921-1922
        Box/Folder 28: 11-12
      - Personnel, 1921-1922 (Reel 41)
        Box/Folder 28: 13
      - Publicity, 1922
        Box/Folder 28: 14
      - Miscellany, 1921-1922
        Box/Folder 28: 15
    - Virginia Hospital, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 28: 16
    - Publicity, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 28: 17
    - Relief work, map of Commission for Serbia, 1919
      Box/Folder 28: 18
    - Miscellany, 1920-1921
      Box/Folder 28: 19
- Commission for Belgium, 1914-1922
  - Index, 1917-1919
    Box/Folder 28: 20
  - ARC National Headquarters, Washington, D.C., 1917-1919
    - General correspondence, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 28: 21-23
    - General correspondence, 1918-1919
      Box/Folder 29: 1-2
    - Director, Bureau of Communication, W.R. Castle, 1917
      Box/Folder 29: 3
  - Switzerland, 1914-1919
    - General correspondence, 1918-1919.
      Box/Folder 29: 4. Includes Rapport Général de l'Oeuvre des Réfugiés Belges en Suisse by Bureau du Comité Central, Lausanne, 1918: and "'Oeuvre Suisse' in Belgium," Zurich, 1918
    - Materials for report on the Belgian children work of the ARC in Switzerland, 1919
      Box/Folder 29: 5
    - "Hospitalisation des Enfants Belges en Gruyère," photo album, 1914-1919
      Box/Folder 29: 6
  - Paris Headquarters, 1917-1919
    - Correspondence, 1918-1919
      - General, 1918
        Box/Folder 29: 7
      - Frederick S. Hoppin, director, Publicity Department, 1917-1918
        Box/Folder 29: 8-9
      - Grace V. Bicknell, Secretary to Commission for Belgium, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 29: 10-12
      - Ernest P. Bicknell, Commissioner for Belgium, 1918 (Reel 42)
        Box/Folder 29: 13
      - Department of Social and Economic Conditions, 1917
        Box/Folder 29: 14
      - Children's Bureau, 1918
        Box/Folder 29: 15
      - Department of Civil Affairs, 1917-1919
        Box/Folder 29: 16
      - Military Affairs, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 29: 17
      - Decorations, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 29: 18
      - Decorations by the Queen, undated
        Box/Folder 29: 19
      - Organizations receiving aid, 1919
        Box/Folder 29: 20
      - Letters of thanks, 1917
        Box/Folder 29: 21-22
      - Letters of thanks, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 30: 1
    - Publicity, 1918-1919
      - Photographs, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 30: 2
      - Articles for publication, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 30: 3-7
      - Clippings, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 30: 8
      - Clippings, 1918-1919 (Reel 43)
        Box/Folder 30: 9-10
      - Le Soir, #90, Brussels, March 31, 1919
        Box/Folder 30: 11